## **Ratchapol Marmongkol**

**Github:** github.com/mratchapol **Email:** ratchapolhappy@gmail.com

Mobile: +66 888712331 Address: Lak Si, Bangkok



#### **SUMMARY**

Equipped with German Language Major, <u>Computer Science Minor</u>, plus experience in <u>Master's in Computer Science</u>, I have <u>passion for Java</u> and I am seeking Java developer role. I have 3-year experience in writing Java, still 0 years in career. I am highly adaptable and do not stop improving myself. Proud to add that I am also language enthusiast.

### **EDUCATION**

Master of Computer Science 2022 - 2024

Thammasat University; GPA: 3.33

Bachelor in Liberal Arts, German Language 2018 - 2021

Thammasat University; GPA: 3.34

Triam Udom Suksa School 2015 - 2017

English-German program

#### **SKILLS**

• Languages Java 🚉 , SQL, HTML (confident) | CSS, Python, C++, JavaScript

- Strong understanding of principles of OOP
- Good understanding of Collections framework and basic data structure
- Good understanding of SQL
- Good understanding of Maven, Spring Boot annotations that handle REST API, dependency injection, and basic exceptions

• Frameworks Spring Boot Opening Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-Learn

Tools MySQL, PostgreSQL, GitPlatforms Eclipse, NetBeans, AWS

 ETL data pipeline using AWS EC2, S3, Cloud9, Glue, Athena, and QuickSight

• Other skills Reading Java Doc skill, Unix Command, Adaptability

English TOEIC 795, German Goethe-Zertifikat B1, Japanese JLPT N5

# WORK EXPERIENCE

Work and Travel Program in the US

May 2024 - September 2024

Performed houseman and housekeeping tasks in hotel

#### Project Coordinator, Pasona Recruitment (Thailand) Jan 2022 - Sept 2023

- Liaised with HR managers and officers from over 20 companies, scheduled and followed up on meetings
- Served as point of communication between internal and external stakeholders
- Manage project-related paperwork, quotations, invoices, receipts from more than 10 vendors, including monitoring expenses and timeline

### Internship, Directorate of Intelligence, Royal Thai Air Force. June 2021 - July 2021

• Translated and summaried news and magazine related to military and air force



